# Andrés Iglesias



aiglesias.rossini@gmail.com andresiglesias.net





https://www.linkedin.com/pub/andr%C3%A9s-iglesias/52/857/316

Software Engineer with more than 4 years of experience in the full Software Development Lifecycle (SDLC). I'm particularly interested in the development of web and mobile applications. Also interested in agile development, UI design, open data, accessibility and Ruby.

### TECHNICAL EXPERTISE

- Languages: Java (JEE, JSF, Servlets, JSP), SQL, PL/SQL, JAVASCRIPT, HTML, CSS, RUBY, PYTHON, OBJECTIVE-C, VISUAL BASIC . NET.
- Databases: Oracle (9, 11), MySQL, PostgreSQL 9, SQLite3
- Application/Web Servers: GlassFish (3, 4), Oracle Application Server, Heroku
- IDE: Eclipse, Netbeans, Xcode
- Frameworks: Ruby on Rails (3, 4), JSF (1.2, 2), Bootstrap 3 (Front-end)
- SDK: iOS SDK 8
- Version control & Automation tools: SVN, GIT, Maven
- Other tools: SoapUI

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## Central Bank of Uruguay, Montevideo, Uruguay Software Engineer

Feb.2014-Present

The job consists of requirement analysis, design, development and testing of internal and external applications.

## Central Bank of Uruguay, Montevideo, Uruguay Consultant

Apr.2011-Feb.2014

The job involved developing web applications using Java technologies such as JSF and support for users of those applications.

# Alterante, Montevideo, Uruguay

Jul.2013-Jan.2014

## Software / QA Developer

Worked for a Silicon Valley based company developing and testing a personal cloud application using Java language.

## TEACHING EXPERIENCE

Universidad Católica del Uruguay, Montevideo, Uruguay Mar.2015-Present Graduate Teaching Assistant Systems Simulation

## PERSONAL PROJECTS

CambiosUY Dec.2014

iOS App (https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/cambiosuy/id951769669?mt=8)

App to be updated to the latest currency exchange rates in Uruguay. Developed for iOS using Xcode.

Reciclalo May.2014

Rails Web app (<a href="http://www.reciclalo.com">http://www.reciclalo.com</a>)

App to find recycling centers in the city. All the information comes from the users as well as open data sources. Developed in Ruby on Rails.

## **EDUCATION**

Universidad Católica del Uruguay, Montevideo, Uruguay

PROFESSIONAL LICENCES & CERTIFICATIONS

2008-2012

**Certified ScrumMaster** 

Computer Engineer

Dec.2012-Present

Scrum Alliance

**Certificate in Advanced English** 

Jul.2012

University of Cambridge ESOL Examinations

#### OTHER INFORMATION

Nationalities: Uruguayan and Italian